<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Accelerator project journal</title>
    <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Accelerator project journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 09:00:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Half way through - what&#39;s left to do</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/mid-point-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 09:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/mid-point-plan/</guid>
      <description>I have 6 or 7 weeks left. Which is basically 6 or 7 days + however much of my own time I can spend on it. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot left to do.
I think there are broadly 5 things for me to focus on, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to achieve everything.
1. Get more data in  Add in data from the last week Tokenize and stem queries so similar ones can be grouped together Investigate whether it makes sense to group queries with the same result sets  2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half way through - what I&#39;ve done so far</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/half-way-through/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/half-way-through/</guid>
      <description>We are half way through the accelerator program and Thursday morning I had a half day meeting and retrospective with the other accelerants. It was really good to have a chance to talk to everyone, but I&amp;rsquo;m finding the limited time very stressful.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet whether the program is going to be 11 or 12 weeks, because we started a week late but there is a venue booking for presentations at the end which hasn&amp;rsquo;t been changed yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting search result relevance with a click model</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/dynamic-bayesian-network-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/dynamic-bayesian-network-model/</guid>
      <description>For my project I want to use search logs to model user behaviour on GOV.UK search.
The approach I want to follow is based on a paper titled A Dynamic Bayesian Network Click Model for Web Search Ranking (Chapelle and Zhang 2009)
Overview of the paper The Dynamic Bayesian Network model is one of many click models for modelling search behaviour in terms of random variables. Given a search engine result page, a click model should be able to predict the probability that a user will click on any of the links on the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 update</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/week-4-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/week-4-update/</guid>
      <description>I postponed my project day on week 4, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to make up the time next week instead. This week I joined a new team at work, and I also had some data issues to work out, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d make better use of my time this way. I can hopefully work on it uninterrupted on Thursday and Friday.
So this week I&amp;rsquo;ve just been working on the project when I&amp;rsquo;ve had free time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve written code to extract the data I need and I&amp;rsquo;ve also loaded it into a postgres database so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to query.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data problems</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/not-getting-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/not-getting-data/</guid>
      <description>This week was really unproductive. I hit some roadblocks with the data so I didn&amp;rsquo;t accomplish what I set out to do on Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;m finding this really stressful at the moment as I&amp;rsquo;m really worried that I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to get the data I need to actually do the project I proposed. 😞
What I planned to do Thursday My aim for this weak was to work out how to use Google BigQuery to fetch the data I need instead of the google Analytics API, because:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting some data</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/getting-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/getting-data/</guid>
      <description>This week my main goal was to get some data and explore it.
I spent most of it figuring out how the Google Analytics API works. I found this quite daunting at first because the &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; documentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t link to a proper reference, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good understanding of the concepts behind google analytics. But I found a couple of useful resources:
 The dimensions and metrics explorer gave me most of the information I needed to query the API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does GOV.UK search work at the moment?</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/background-govuk-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/background-govuk-search/</guid>
      <description>The search functionality on GOV.UK is built using an open source search engine, Elasticsearch.
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how GOV.UK search uses elasticsearch to generate search results, and some of the problems with it.
Indexing Whenever a new document is published, it automatically gets added to a search index. When you index a document, elasticsearch analyses the document&amp;rsquo;s text, which involves lowercasing, stripping out diacretics, breaking it into tokens, stemming words, substituting synonyms etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About this project</title>
      <link>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/what-is-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 13:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matmoore.github.io/accelerator/post/what-is-this/</guid>
      <description>Hi! Over the next 3 months I&amp;rsquo;m going to be spending 1 day a week working on a project as part of the government data science accelerator programme. I&amp;rsquo;m encouraged to keep a journal and I thought a blog would be a good way to do it.
Background I currently work as a software developer on GOV.UK, the website used by people in the UK to access government services and information online.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>